(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T04:29:16.532981",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ReGLOSS MINI LIVE Sakura Mirage 2025.03.30 (SUN) 20:00 Start
[ReGLOSS MINI LIVE: Sakura Mirage - March 30, 2025 (Sun) 20:00 Start]
漠然とした不安
Vague anxiety,
欲しかったfun
fun I was craving.
日常に違和感？
A sense of discomfort in daily life?
うんざりしていた
I was fed up with it.
見慣れたありきたりな眺め
The familiar, mundane scenery.
理屈を超える変化を求めていた
Seeking a change that goes beyond logic.
窮屈で退屈な日々の中
In these cramped and boring days,
突然キミは現れた
suddenly you appeared.
全身の細胞駆け巡るように
Running through every cell in my body,
走り出した未完成なストーリー
a new, unfinished story began to run.
モノクロだった景色が今
The scenery that was once monochrome,
キミと出会いカラフルに彩る brand new world
now becomes colorful, a brand new world.
ココロ奪われた
My heart was stolen,
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
a capricious moment's heartbeat.
揺らぐ時空の狭間
In the gap of swaying space-time,
もうひとりじゃない煌めく星
I am no longer alone, a sparkling star.
描く未来予想図は
The future projection I draw,
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
I want to draw the same dream closer.
果てしない旅路の向こうで
Beyond the endless journey,
鳴り止まないロマンが待っている
an unceasing romance is waiting.
気づいた時にはね
When I noticed it, you know,
i can't live without you
ココロ奪われた
My heart was stolen,
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
a capricious moment's heartbeat.
揺らぐ時空の狭間
In the gap of swaying space-time,
もうひとりじゃない煌めく星
I am no longer alone, a sparkling star.
描く未来予想図は
The future projection I draw,
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
I want to draw the same dream closer.
果てしない旅路の向こうで
Beyond the endless journey,
紛れもない奇跡があるはずさ
there must be an undeniable miracle.
さよならメランコリック
Goodbye, melancholic,
止められはしないこの衝動
I can't stop this impulse.
突き進むだけさ
I'll just charge forward,
are you ready?
限界はないさ純度無限大の異次元
There is no limit, a different dimension with infinite purity.
散りばめた閃き夜空溢れていく
The scattered flashes fill the night sky.
喜びは悲しみの倍分かち合っていこう
Let's share joy, doubling our sorrows.
キミとならどこまでも
If I'm with you, I can go anywhere.
漠然とした不安 欲しかったfun
Vague anxiety, the fun I wanted
日常の違和感？うんざりしてた
A sense of discomfort in daily life? I was sick of it
見慣れたありきたりな眺め
A familiar, ordinary view
理屈を超える変化を求めていた
I was looking for changes beyond reason
窮屈で退屈な日々の中
Amidst cramped and boring days
突然キミは現れた
You suddenly appeared
全身の細胞駆け巡るように
As if running through every cell in my body
走り出した未完成なストーリー
An unfinished story started running
モノクロだった景色が今
The monochrome scenery now
キミと出会いカラフルに彩る brand new world
Colors colorfully with you, brand new world
ココロ奪われた
My heart was stolen
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
A whimsical momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
In the gap of swaying spacetime
もうひとりじゃない煌めく星
A sparkling star, no longer alone
描く未来予想図は
The future forecast we draw
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
I want to draw the same dream closer
果てしない旅路の向こうで
Beyond the endless journey
鳴りやまないロマンが待っている
A ceaseless romance awaits
気づいたときには i can't live without you
Before I knew it, I can't live without you
いつまでもキミと一緒なら
If I'm with you forever
ここから先広がる宇宙
The universe spreading out from here
晴れ渡る空飛び出して
Flying out into the clear sky
気分は上々想像以上
Feeling's high, beyond imagination
机上の空論は終わりにして
Let's end armchair theories
すべて叶える絵空事
Idle fancies that make everything come true
時計の針が回り回り
The clock hands spin round and round
限られた時間の中で鮮やかに dancing time
Vividly dancing time within limited time
ココロ奪われた
My heart was stolen
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
A whimsical momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
In the gap of swaying spacetime
もうひとりじゃない煌めく星
A sparkling star, no longer alone
描く未来予想図は
The future forecast we draw
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
I want to draw the same dream closer
果てしない旅路の向こうで
Beyond the endless journey
紛れもない奇跡があるはず
There must be an unmistakable miracle
さようならメランコリック
Goodbye, melancholic
止められはしないこの衝動
This urge that cannot be stopped
突き進むだけさ
Just charging forward
形振り構わず are you ready？
Regardless of appearance, are you ready?
限界はないさ純度無限大の異次元
There's no limit, an infinite purity dimension
散らばり始めた閃き夜空満ちていく
The scattered flashes fill the night sky
喜びは哀しみの倍分かち合っていこう キミとならどこまでも
Let's share the joy twice as much as sorrow if I'm with you anywhere
お馴染みこの挨拶やりよー！
Let's do our usual greeting!
リーサタプ、ウィア、リグロス！
ReGLOSS tap, we are ReGLOSS!
お水も飲みながらだけど、自己紹介いつもの順番でよろしくー！
While drinking water, let's do self-introductions in the usual order!
えー、そしたら下から行きます！
Um, in that case, we'll start from the bottom!
ほろライブデバイスタグロスの一条莉々華よ、みんなめっちゃ緊張してます！てか、みてみて！
Hololive Device ReGLOSS's Ichijo Ririka! Everyone, I'm super nervous! Wait, look, look!
これみてみて、髪の毛がすごいな！
Look at this, my hair is amazing!
そしてー！
And then—!
はい、可愛いポジティブジニアス、ホロライブデバイスタグロスの一条莉々華よ、まためちゃくちゃ緊張してます！
Yes, cute positive genius, Hololive Device ReGLOSS's Ichijo Ririka! I'm super nervous again!
むっちゃ走って、めちゃ元気だな！
Running like crazy, so energetic!
え、元気だな、そして、こっち！
Uh, so energetic, and over here!
はい、ホロライブデバイスホロライブデバイスタグロスの一条莉々華ね、ちょっと待って！上手く言えなかったんだけど！
Yes, Hololive Device ReGLOSS's Ichijo Ririka, wait! I couldn't say it well!
自己紹介、上手く言えたことないんですけど！みなさん楽しんでますか？
I've never said my self-introduction well! Are you all having fun?
ふんふんふん、ホロライブデバイスタグロスの番長、続き始める！
Fun fun fun, ReGLOSS's Bancho, continuing now!
ちょっと先ほど発表がありました通り、青くんは現在活動休止しているため
As announced earlier, Ao-kun is currently on hiatus, so
今回のミニライブは青くんの分もやり抜きたいと思います！
for this mini-live, we want to get through it including Ao-kun's share!
ちなみにさっきの曲「瞬間ハートビーティング」だったけどさ、この曲はもう披露めカウントダウンでも今回で3回目でしょう？
By the way, the previous song was "Shunkan Heartbeating", but this was the 3rd time counting premiere countdowns?
だから、まあリリカ的にはまあまあ緊張もちょっと落ち着いてきたかなって感じだったんだけど
So, well, for Ririka, my tension had calmed down a bit, but
いや、待て、一番緊張してた！でも緊張しちゃうのは仕方ないもんだよねこういうのは。
No wait, I was the most nervous! But it's natural to get nervous about things like this.
番長はどう？なんか楽しくパフォーマンスできたなって思います！
How about Bancho? I feel like we were able to perform really enjoyably!
前回、前々回より、どんどん揃ってきてる！
Compared to last time and the time before, we're getting more and more in sync!
本当にそう！ハクロちょか、なんか色々ね、うんうんうん。でもね、ほら綺麗じゃん！
Really true! Hakuro-choka, and various things, yeah. But look, it's pretty!
汐音ちゃんはどうだった？本当に楽しくて、コメントの皆さんも応援見てりましてありがとうございます！
How was Shione-chan? It was really fun, and thank you everyone in the comments for watching and supporting!
もう瞬間ハートビーティングの前にさ、ほら私らヘリコプターに乗ってさ、登場しましたけど
Before "Shunkan Heartbeating", you know, we rode helicopters and appeared,
あれ乗ってる間私これ酔って歌えなかったらどうしようって思いながらずっと、「よくないよ、よくないよ」言いながらさ（笑）
and while riding that, I kept thinking "what if I get carsick and can't sing", saying "this isn't good, this isn't good" (laughs)
無事、無事でした！よかった！よかった！
We were safe! Good! Good!
あとカバアシャの一番上っていうね、すごいねこんなところががあったなんて！
Also being at the very top of Kabaasha, it's amazing there was a place like this!
お天気に恵まれ絶好のライブ日和！
Blessed with good weather, perfect live weather!
今日はReGLOSSの新曲である「サクラミラージュ」のお披露目を兼ねたミニライブとなっております！
Today is a mini-live serving as the premiere of ReGLOSS's new song "Sakura Mirage"!
くれたよねぇ！
You gave it to us, right?!
どうですか？
How is it?
おっつおっつ！お疲れ様！
Good job! Good work!
でもね、みんなちょっとラグがあるね
Though, everyone has a bit of lag.
あるね、でもね嬉しいね
There is, but still, we're happy!
ちょっと優しくして打ってね、みんな
Everyone, type it a bit gently, please!
頼んだよ～
I'm counting on you~
イェーイ！
Yay!
そしてね、ライブの感想はハッシュタグ、今この上にも出てると思うんですけど、ReGLOSS 3Dライブでいっぱいポストしていただければと思います！
And for your live impressions, please post a lot using the hashtag #ReGLOSS3DLive!
よろしくお願いします！一緒にお願いします！
Please do! Please join us!
ま、今日ね、まあお天気にも恵まれましたが、なんかちょっといつも
Well, today we were blessed with good weather, but
よりさらにカメラ綺麗だと思いませんか、皆さん！ラベちゃ痩せた？
don't you think the camera quality is even clearer than ever, everyone?!
いや、そういうことじゃない、そういうことじゃないか
No, that's not what I mean - or is it?
いやこれね、しかもイヤモニですよ！イヤモニ！
And this is with in-ear monitors! In-ears!
イヤジアー！イヤジアー！
Ear-ia! Ear-ia!
いいね、これ各自のね、ちょっとカラーで以前作った動画も上がったと思うんですけど、それをつけてやっています！イェーイ！
Nice, we're doing this wearing the custom-colored ones from the video we posted before! Yay!
ちなみに、今日のステージの演出もすごくらしくて、パンチャー、いつものお願いします！
By the way, the stage production today is also very us, Puncher, please do the usual!
まあまあ、勝ち時計な？え、何？おっけー。
Well well, winning clock? Eh, what? Okay.
ファイヤー！ボーン！
Fire! Boom!
スーパークラダよー！
Super Kurada-yo!
スーパークラダよ？
Super Kurada-yo?
えー？スパークラ？なんだかよく分かんない
Eh? Sparkura? I don't really get it.
いや分かる分かる、知ってるよ！いや、スパークラー！入れやスパークラ！
No I know I know, I know it! Sparkler!
ジャーン！すごーい！今回めちゃ
Ta-da! Amazing! This time so...
はい、という感じでかなり色々なことやってもらえるところなんだけど、まだまだいろんな仕掛けはありますので、
Right, so we get to do a lot of various things like that, but there are still plenty of other gimmicks to come,
この後も皆さん楽しみにしていていただければと思います！イェーイ！
so we hope you'll look forward to what's next! Yay!
ちょっとリーガ息切れしてんだけど、みんなもう歌いける？あ、ちょっと水飲んできたが
Rii-ga is running out of breath, can everyone still sing? Ah, having had some water...
アイドル、アイドル、アイドルでございます！今日はライブということでね！
We are idols, idols, idols! Since today is a live!
はい！なんか、雲...曇って来た...本当だ！
Yes! Somehow, clouds... it's getting cloudy... true!
天気が...お天気に恵まれるとか言っとったのに！お前が！
The weather... even though you said we'd be blessed with good weather! You did!
じゃあね、早速歌聴いてもらえればと思います。歌うたメイビーとシンメトリー2曲続けていきたいと思います！
Well then, let's have you listen to a song right away. We'd like to continue with two songs, Utakata Maybe and Symmetry!
よーし、じゃあみんなね、緊張するからね。じゃあ行きましょうか、聞いてください、歌方メイビー
Alright, everyone, we're nervous. Well then, shall we go? Please listen, Utakata Maybe.
嵐の前みたいな静けさ 触れた温度はまだアンニュイ
The calm before the storm, the touch still feels languid
一喜一憂 過ぎたエウレカ 尽きるまでは冷えない探究心
A roller coaster of emotions, the eureka moment is past, my curiosity won't cool until exhausted
立ち止まれば 目の前には 振り返ったときの自分がいて
When I stop, in front of me, I see the self I left behind
小声で囁くシルエット ぼやけて 何も聞こえないphrase
A silhouette whispers softly, but it blurs, and I can't hear a thing
泡沫メイビー 回れ右、今夜 分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right, tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎ レイニー 繰り返し、さよなら 溜め息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating, a sigh of goodbye
ほんの ちょっとの あいだの 停滞 燻ぶったままの 低体温
A brief stagnation, with low body temperature smoldering
失った 過去も 少し 手痛い？ 今は まだ 見過ごしていたいよ
The past I've lost stings a little—for now, I still want to overlook it
空が 白んで 睫毛 濡らした あと 一つ 何か が 足りないんだ
The sky brightens, wetting my eyelids—something is still missing
充電 みたいな エヴリデイ すべて 青天の霹靂
Every day feels like recharging, everything a bolt from the blue
遠巻きの バイタリティ いつも 記憶が 愛らしい
A distant vitality, always the memories are endearing
変哲の ない 日々 の 破片 散らばって 立ち往生してる
Fragments of ordinary days scattered around, leaving me stranded
ずっと 微風に 黄昏れていたいの 雲隠れした 淡い期待
I want to keep being embraced by the gentle breeze, lost in twilight, fleeting hopes hidden behind clouds
泡沫メイビー 回れ右、今夜 分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right, tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎ レイニー 繰り返し、さよなら 溜め息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating, a sigh of goodbye
痺れるような 幕開けを ただ じっと 待っている day & night
Waiting silently for a thrilling new beginning, day and night
雲と雲の 切り間から rays of light shining
Rays of light shining through the gaps between clouds
「もう 後ろを 振り返らないで」 そう 呟いたんだ
"Don't look back anymore," I whispered to myself
嵐の前みたいな静けさ 触れた温度はまだアンニュイ
The calm before the storm, the touch still feels languid
一喜一憂 過ぎたエウレカ 尽きるまでは冷えない探究心
A roller coaster of emotions, the eureka moment is past, my curiosity won't cool until exhausted
立ち止まれば 目の前には 振り返ったときの自分がいて
When I stop, in front of me, I see the self I left behind
小声で囁くシルエット ぼやけて 何も聞こえないphrase
A silhouette whispers softly, but it blurs, and I can't hear a thing
泡沫メイビー 回れ右、今夜 分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right, tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎ レイニー 繰り返し、さよなら 溜め息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating, a sigh of goodbye
痺れるような 幕開けを ただ じっと 待っている day & night
Waiting silently for a thrilling new beginning, day and night
嵐の前みたいな静けさ 触れた温度はまだアンニュイ
The calm before the storm, the touch still feels languid...
泡沫メイビー 回り右、今夜分かれ道
Ephemeral maybe, turning right, tonight's the crossroads
胸騒ぎのレイニー 繰り返し、さらば溜め息
A restless rainy feeling, repeating, a sigh of goodbye
ほんのちょっとのあいだの停滞 燻ったままの低体温
A brief stagnation, with low body temperature smoldering
失った過去も少し手痛い？ 今はまだ見過ごしていたいよ
The past I've lost stings a little — for now, I still want to overlook it
痺れるような寝癖だけは ただじっと待っている day & night
The messy hair feeling numb, I'm just waiting patiently day & night
雲と雲の切れ間から rays of light shining
Rays of light shining through the gaps between the clouds
もう後ろを振り返らないで そう呟いたんだ
"Don't look back anymore," I whispered to yourself.
さだめ雲町を牽制
Holding down the predestined town,
かき消すようにゲレンデを走って
running down the slopes as if erasing it,
一心不乱に叫ぶここで
shouting with single-minded devotion right here.
割れた爪を眺めてる暇もないよ
I don't even have time to look at my cracked nails.
時の流れに飲み込まれたっていい
It's fine if I get swallowed by the flow of time,
立ち塞がる壁に
against the wall blocking my way,
窓から迎え音
waiting for the welcoming sound from the window.
パッと見はだらけ君が続ければマスターピース
At a glance, if you, looking lazy, keep going, it's a masterpiece.
座りすべて食いいただけ努力だけは裏切らない
Eating everything while sitting down, only effort won't betray you.
毎度の先頭線 イスパイア戦闘で
Every time at the front line, inspired in battle,
晴れてるヘトセ ずっとずっと手ごめ
clear head... keeping on struggling.
歯車探した峠道
The mountain pass where we searched for gears,
静かにともす青い炎
quietly lighting a blue flame.
たしょう声んでも怖い今日 じっと見つめ合って
Even if it's a bit noisy, today is scary, staring intently at each other.
駆けてく旋律のよ 行こう憧れて先に連れて
Running melody's night, let's go, longing and leading ahead,
失ないかけた夢の続きを紡いでいこう
let's weave the continuation of the lost dream.
凍えた世界を満たしてメロディ響く夜
Filling a frozen world, the melody echoes tonight,
君と行き重なるシンメトリー確信寄せる朝のほうへ
Symmetry overlapping with you, toward the morning of growing conviction.
こんな微妙なニュアンスの違い 絶妙なバランスの甘い目
Such subtle nuance differences, the sweet eyes of exquisite balance.
すべての歯車たちは巧妙に噛み合っている
All the gears are engaging intricately.
数学より冷たい赤い マイクの片寄ったパラダイム 人と成り合わせてたい
Colder than mathematics, a red microphone's biased paradigm, wanting to align with people.
これのきっと誰かのanother life 君だけも私だけも 今だけを国に開きよ
This is surely someone's another life, only you, only me, opening only now to the country.
狭い終えの足をどう 願い事叶わなくとも
No matter if wishes don't come true for the feet at the narrow end,
始まりはなぜ遠いと 気をひそめて
why is the beginning so far? Hiding my breath...
静寂を切り裂いて 空へ羽ばたかせ重ねて
Cutting through the silence, spreading wings toward the sky and overlapping.
待ち望む結末に回ったって粋じゃできないよ
Waiting for the climax, it's not chic if you turn back.
どんな形も傷もかすれた微風寄せて飛び越え
No matter what shape or scar, bringing a faint, fading breeze and leaping over,
今更ねわけに秘めた思い もう後戻りはしない
thoughts hidden in the reason now, I won't turn back anymore.
駆けてく旋律のよ 行こう憧れて先に連れて
Running melody's night, let's go, longing and leading ahead,
失ないかけた夢の続きを紡いでいこう
let's weave the continuation of the lost dream.
凍えた世界を満たしてメロディ響く夜
Filling a frozen world, the melody echoes tonight,
君と行き重なるシンメトリー確信寄せる朝のほうへ
Symmetry overlapping with you, toward the morning of growing conviction.
すごい！
That's amazing!
すごい、どこに、え？ 行けとるやん！
It's incredible!
何これ。ねえ、慣れずら。慣れずら。
Getting used to it is hard.
確かにね。
That's true.
まあ、雨もだけど、いつの間にかこんな素敵な夕暮れになってて。
It's already such a lovely dusk.
ねえ！
Right?
めちゃめちゃきれい！
It's so pretty!
これ、あの、カメラ引きで、これすごい、あ、気付いた？ みんなさ、
Wait, did you guys notice?
ステージのさ、外枠の形が、あのホロライブデバイスのエインターキーのマークになってんの！
The outer frame of the stage has the Hololive Device's enter-key mark on it!
の、夜になってからわかりやすいけど。
You can tell better from the night view, but...
確かにライトでね、わかりやすくなったんだ。すげえ！
It became easier to see with the lights! That's amazing!
チャプチャプするんだよね、ね。
It chug-chugs, right?
水が跳ねるのがすごい！
The water splashing is amazing!
いや、こんなところでさ、まだあるから！やばいやばいやばい、待って待って、しなきゃいけない。
Wait, let's stop splashing water in a place like this, there's still more!
水飲んでる。
We're drinking water!
そうだね。
That's right.
え、どうだっけ？ シンメトリーと「シンメトリーと常夜恋ベイベー」は、3D初お披露目だって。
It's the first time we've revealed 3D versions of "Shinmeichori"!
ねえ！
Really?
めっちゃ久しぶりなのにお披露目初めて？
It's been so long, but it's the first time?
初めて？ いやそこ初めてじゃない。２周年行ってないから。
It's the first time in two years!
うまく、なっちゃったかな。
Did it go well?
どうでしたか、みなさん。
How was it, everyone?
どうだったよ。
Did you like it?
一、一般グロースやりましたね。
We did a full, raw version!
からのお水飲んでくる。
Go drink some water!
いってらっしゃい。
Welcome back!
待って今何話してたの？
Wait, what were we just talking about?
あの、「シンメトリー」と「常夜恋ベイベー」は3Dお披露目以来だねって話。
Ah, "Shinmeichori" and "Tsukiyo Koi Baby" are being performed in 3D for the first time ever!
そうだよね。
That's right.
でも、なんかもう、２曲目３曲目だから、から、わかんないけど。
Well, for the second and third songs, I'm not sure...
ちょっと緊張がほぐれて、今疲れてるからだめだけどさ。
The tension has worn off, and we're tired, so that's no good.
水行ってこい。
Go drink water and come back!
っていうわけね。
So that's how it is!
次の曲は？
What about the next song?
あ、まだ番長持ってきてない。あ、違う違う違う。
Wait, we haven't even decided the order yet!
あ、そういうことか。次の曲について喋れって。
Oh, talk about the song!
綿あめ、綿あめ、綿あめ、綿あめ、綿あめ。
Cotton candy, cotton candy.
今、10万人が見とる。
Right now, 10 million people are watching!
バカな。10万人の前でやることバカめで。
It's obvious it's 10 million people watching!
綺麗に分かり、ありがとうございます！
Well, thank you very much!
なになにこれ？
What's this?
新しいミーム？
New?
非常口になるよ、また。
It's going to become an emergency exit.
蟹はかもしれん。
Crabs might be...
びっくりして噎せちゃった。
I got so startled I choked!
ねえ、まあ、サクラミラージュが3Dで初お披露目となるわけだけど、
Well, Sakura Mirage is being performed in 3D for the first time, which is why...
蟹、もう振り付け見せてないもんね。
Crab, you haven't shown us any choreography yet!
ねえ、蟹以外はまだね、みんな知らないからさ、ちょっとせっかくだし、
Yeah, except for Crab, nobody else knows it yet, so since we have the chance...
この曲のイメージをポーズで表してみない？
Try expressing the image of this song with a pose!
長らね。
Show us!
いいねいいね！
Good, good, good!
じゃあ番長行く？ おきあ。行くじゃん。
Let's go, Bancho!
おー！妖精みたいな。
Wow, like a fairy!
森の妖精さんかな？
Could she be a forest fairy?
可愛い！
That's cute!
桜の妖精のような動きだね。
She looks like a cherry blossom fairy!
ちょっと、こんな感じじゃない？
Isn't that just a weird pose?
いいね！
Good!
じゃあ次進んでいきます！
Next, let's keep going!
それは何？
What was that?
桜の木から、それわかめだろ！
It's a cherry blossom tree... wait, that's seaweed!
わかめじゃないの？
Isn't that seaweed?
に飛ばされたね、わかめがちっちゃって。
She got blown away by the wind!
わかめりりか。
That's Wakame Ririka!
行きます！
Let's go!
ダイナミック！
Dynamic!
ダイナミック、ダイナミック！
So dynamic!
これぐらい跳べるんだぜってことを見せてやりたかった。
I wanted to show how much it can jump!
カメラこっちだった。
The camera was over there!
はい、やっと。
There you go!
じゃあ、りりか。
Then, Ririka!
これでしょう。
This is it!
違う違う！くねくねやん！
That's different! That's just swaying!
違った違った、くねくねよ。
It's different, it's different, swaying back and forth!
この４人の中で誰が一番イメージと近かったか、皆さん予想して当ててみてください。
Out of the four of us, who was closest to the image? Guess and try to guess, everyone!
それやるんだったら、別のやつやるんだよ！
If we're gonna do that, let's do a different one!
マジでだよ！
Seriously!
真面目にやったんちゃうんか。
We should've done it seriously!
愛ちゃんの、じゃあ行きますか？
Well, then, shall we go?
もうやっちゃうんですか？
Are we going to do it now?
そんな新曲聞いていただいちゃいますか？
Won't you listen to our new song?
準備できそう？
Is it ready?
ぜはぜは、え、これ何、シンメトリー？
Zehazeha... Wait, what is this, symmetry?
あれ、シンメトリーじゃないの？いつから始まる？
Wait, it's not symmetry! When does it start?
よし、それでは新曲聴いてください。
Alright, then please listen to our new song!
サクラミラージュ！
Sakura Mirage!
staring into your eyes make me feel alive
それは始まりの合図
That is the starting signal.
are you ready for this ？
Are you ready for this?
柔らかな風 ほら、春めいて
A soft breeze, look, spring has come
共鳴するファンファーレ
Resonating fanfare
桜花爛漫 染める桃色
Cherry blossoms in full bloom, dyeing everything in peach pink
別れの予感はソメイヨシノ
The premonition of parting is a daydream
i'll be there, i'll be there, i'll be there, i'll be there for you
一閃浴びて dance with me now！！
Bathed in a flash, dance with me now!
音も立てず交わす キミとのコントラスト
Exchanging the contrast with you without even making a sound
その余白はいつかのため
Leaving that white space for later
save the best for last
小さく震えた lip
A slightly trembling lip
噛み締めるまだ微熱の real
Biting down on the still warm real
本音の speaker ダイレクトな weaver
True speaker, direct weaver
解き放て on my mind
Unleashed on my mind
春が来た パッと サクラミラージュ
Spring has come, in a flash, Sakura Mirage
staring into your eyes make me feel alive
それは始まりの合図
That is the signal of the beginning
Are you ready for this?
柔らかな風 ほら、春めいて
Soft wind, look, it feels like spring
共鳴するファンファーレ
A resounding fanfare
桜花爛漫 染める桃色
Cherry blossoms in full bloom, dyeing everything pink
別れの予感はソメイヨシノ
The premonition of farewell is Somei Yoshino
I'll be there, I'll be there,
I'll be there, I'll be there for you
一閃浴びて dance with me now!!
Bathed in a flash, dance with me now!!
音も立てず交わす
Exchanging silently
キミとのコントラスト
Contrast with you
その余白はいつかのため
That margin is for sometime
Save the best for last
あれ？
Huh?
あれ？ あれ？
Huh? Huh?
もう1回遊べるってこと？
Does that mean we can play again?
どんとはい！
Bring it on!
えー！？ リズム合わせて！
Ehh?! Match the rhythm!
どどんが どどんが どどんが どん！
Don-don-ka, don-don-ka, don-don-ka, don!
皆さん、生配信でお送りしております。
Everyone, we are broadcasting live.
生配信って、それ毎度のいつものやつ。
"Live streaming" — that's the usual thing every time.
ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Please wait a moment.
もう1回やるからちょっと待ってね。もう1回、アビデできるってこと？
We'll do it one more time, so please wait. Can we do ABDE again?
そういうことじゃん。アビデ、アビデ、アビでよー！
That's what it means. ABDE, ABDE, ABDE-yo!
いやもう一回、柔らかな家系呼び起こしは。柔らかな家系呼び起こして。
No, recall the soft family line again. Recall the soft family line.
ちょっとお待ちくださいね、皆さん。
Please wait a moment, everyone.
ちょっと、始まりないず、失敗しちゃったわ。
Wait, the starting cue, I messed it up.
ちょっと？ え？ 失敗してないよ。
Wait? Huh? You didn't mess up.
ああ、そうだそうだそうだ！ わかめやっとく？
Ah, that's right, that's right! Shall we do seaweed?
わかめわかめ！ そんなだれもやらないだろ、これ！
Seaweed seaweed! Nobody's gonna do that, this!
動き出すやん！
It starts moving!
ちょっとだけお待ちくださいね、皆さん。
Please wait just a moment, everyone.
桜といえばゲームする、パンパンって言って。桜？
Speaking of Sakura, playing games, saying "pan-pan". Sakura?
違う違う違う！ 桜といえばだから桜ものので、わかちゃん、わかちゃん。
No no no! Since it's speaking of Sakura, Waka-chan, Waka-chan.
いいよ！ いいよ！ じゃあ私からね。
Alright! Alright! Then from me, okay?
どん！ どん！ 桜餅！ えーー！？ よっしゃー！ よっしゃー！
Don! Don! Sakura mochi! Ehhh?! Yay! Yay!
ちゃんとやって。からだも脱落して。
Do it properly. Drop out physically too.
じゃあ、番長からね。言えよ。桜といえばね。
Then, from Bancho. Say it. Speaking of Sakura.
パン！ パン！ ビニールシート！ パン！ パン！ おだんご！
Pan! Pan! Vinyl sheet! Pan! Pan! Dumpling!
おだんご？ まあまあ、いいでしょう。
Dumpling? Well, well, that's fine.
せーの！ パン！ パン！ お弁当！ パン！ パン！
Ready, go! Pan! Pan! Bento box! Pan! Pan!
桜といえばなの、それ。ピック！ ピック！ お弁当のピック。
What is that for Sakura? Pick! Pick! Bento pick.
中のあの惣菜とか刺さってるやつ。赤いピック。
The one stuck in side dishes. Red pick.
ほい！ パン！ パン！ うん、え？ ピックじゃ、しない。あ、しないんだ。やめたんだ。
Hoi! Pan! Pan! Um, eh? Pick, you don't. Ah, you don't. You quit.
桜ミラージュは、もう大喜利大会になってますやん、これ。
Sakura Mirage has become a comedy variety show contest here.
お花見行きたいね！ お花見行きた。でもなんかちょっと桜っぽくない？
I want to go cherry blossom viewing! I want to go. But isn't it a bit not quite Sakura?
この色味もさ、ピンクがかってるしさ。ねえ！ ピカピカじゃん！
This coloring too, it's tinged with pink. Hey! It's shiny!
ピカピカじゃん！ めちゃくちゃ綺麗じゃん！
It's shiny! It's so pretty!
うわ、ケラミめちゃくちゃ余計なのかな。
Wow, Kerami is being totally redundant.
めちゃくちゃ綺麗！ ペンライトもね、ね、いっぱいいっぱい振ってくれて。
So pretty! The penlights too, everyone, waving them so much.
ペンライト振ってくれてる人！ うわーー！！ いっぱい！
Everyone waving penlights! Wow!! So many!
いやー、なかなかね。まあ、こういうのも生ならではじゃないですか。
Man, it's something. Well, things like this are unique to live performances, right?
こういうトラブルがね、あるっていうのも。
Troubles like this happening.
皆さんもう少々お待ちください！ ちょっと、より可愛くここで歌をレリーズするわ。
Everyone, please wait a little longer! Wait, I'll release the song cutely here.
嘘嘘！ 大丈夫！ 今完璧にやらない。それは初めの挨拶も可愛いからね。
Lies lies! It's fine! Don't do it perfectly now. Because even the initial greeting is cute.
それは初めの挨拶。
That's the initial greeting.
あーかわいい！ ちょっと買いすぎ。
Ah so cute! Buying too much.
違うわ！ ちょっと違うわ！
That's wrong! That's a bit different!
でもちっちゃい可愛いガチャからな、からのアイレディフォーです。
But from that cute gacha, from there it's "I'm ready for this".
可愛い！ 可愛い。やらないの、それ。
Cute! Cute. You're not doing that.
アイレディフォーディ！ 可愛いじゃん！ いいじゃん。じゃ、番長は？ いいよ。
I'm ready for this! Cute, right? That's good. Then Bancho? Okay.
やわらかな金地！ それは春のルンルンパリアリ。
Soft gold ground! That's the spring run-run Pariari.
いつもの通りではないくない？ いつもの通りでいいよ。
Isn't it not according to usual? It's fine as usual.
カナデから見た番長はいつもこうなんだって。
Bancho as seen by Kanade is always like this.
このファンファーレのここ好きなんでね。ファンファーレいいよね。
I love this part of the fanfare. Fanfare is nice.
なんか、指揮者ちゃんみたいなね。ごめん、そこ習ってないからできないわ。
Like a conductor. Sorry, I haven't learned that so I can't do it.
なんか今、まあなんかこんな感じ。
Well, right now, well something like this.
なんかこれやってる時に、もうみんな次のこれに備えてるもんね。アビデに。
While doing this, everyone is already preparing for the next thing. For ABDE.
もう一番今日、どこが一番緊張してる、このアビデだからね。
Today, the part I'm most nervous about is this ABDE.
このラップ長いけん、1回つまずいいたらもう多分だめなんだ。
This rap is long, so if you stumble once, it's probably no good.
あー！ あ、しゅんで、しゅんげ、あ、違う。
Ah! Ah, shunde, shunge, ah, different.
アビデ、アビで、アビで、アビでって、ちょっと。
ABDE, ABDE, ABDE, ABDE, wait.
待って待ってちょっと待って、
Wait, wait, wait, hold on,
ちょっと1回混ぜてみたみたいな
it's like we mixed it in once...
え、ちょっとさ、早速なんだけどさ、
Um, wait, right away,
ちょさっきのさ、踊ったときのさ、ミスの話していい？
can we talk about the mistake when we danced earlier?
あ、いいよ！
Yeah, sure!
足踏んだよね？
You stepped on my foot, right?
え？嘘なのかな
Eh? No way!
おもしろすぎ、え？そうなの？
That's too funny, is that really true?
りりかがすって足……
Ririka just smoothly stepped...
後でみんなアーカイブで見たい、見たいね！
Let's all watch the archive later, yeah, let's watch!
でも全然軽く軽かったからさ、気づいてなかったんだ、気づいてると思ってた。
But it was really light, so I didn't notice. I thought you noticed.
気づいて……気づいてなかったんだ！気づいてたんだ！
I noticed... you didn't notice! You noticed!
おもしろすぎ！おもしろすぎ！やばい！
Too funny! Too funny! No way!
いや、今言ったらおもしろ……おもしろい
No, if you say it now, it's funny...
ちょ、一緒にお水飲んでこようかな
Um, shall we go drink some water together?
はい、じゃあね、このあとみんながお水から戻ってきたら、踊りましょう。
Okay, bye-bye. After everyone comes back from water, let's dance.
そして歌いましょう。
And let's sing.
え、りりか胸のまんなか大丈夫？
Eh, Ririka, is the center of your chest okay?
え？喉くは？
Eh? Your throat?
え？ちょっと待って
Eh? Wait a minute.
喉く、もう一列納得？納得、納得。
Throat, convinced in another row? Convinced, convinced.
シンメトリー始まる？
Does symmetry start?
やるか、もう一回ね。でも一番前以外もやってみたいんだよね。
Shall we do it once more? But I'd like to try other than the very front.
一番前どうしたらいいの？
What should we do in the very front?
なんかふにょふにょふにょって感じ。いや、はんはん
Like squishy squishy squishy. No, hun-hun.
そこまではじゃないかな
Not quite to that extent, right?
すれ違い。
Passing each other.
それでは、改めてまして。
With that said, once again.
え、新曲「サクラミラージュ」聞いてください。はい！
Please listen to our new song, "Sakura Mirage". Yes!
Starting true love メモリーフィリア それは始まりの愛
Starting true love, memory philia, that is the love of the beginning...
柔らかな風 ほら春めいて今日を祝うファンファーレ
Soft wind, look, spring-like, a fanfare celebrating today
臆病なまま染めるよりも色鮮やかな時間は染め上げて
Rather than dyeing timidly, more colorful times...
もっと高くまで変わるずっと君とのコントラスト
Higher and higher, changing, always a contrast with you
その夜明けはいつかのため溜め込むフィルムそう
That dawn is a film stored up for someday, yes
Simple best for life 小さく震えた唇噛み締めまだ熱のリア
Simple best for life, biting my trembling lips, still with the heat
トンネルを抜けてダイレクトなリバー飛び立ておおまま
Passing through the tunnel, direct river, taking flight...
春が来た、サクラミラージュ。咲いて儚いね笑ってエンドレス
Spring has come, Sakura Mirage. Blooming fleetingly, laughing endlessly
揺れながらまだ夢の中へそっと囁いて叶えてStep for me
Swaying, still into a dream, softly whispering, making it come true, step for me
カメラ、カメラ、離さずいくずきまもないLife is ポッパ、ハラビダ
Camera, camera, going without letting go, life with no time to catch breath...
一期一会、今この瞬間を大切にラブストーリーきらり輝いたStay for me
Once-in-a-lifetime encounter, cherishing this very moment, a love story shining brightly, stay for me
ぼやけてしまいそうな動向鏡完璧に描けなくてだってヒーラー
A horizon that seems to blur, unable to draw it perfectly, yet a healer
熱を帯びたまま組み上げるフュマソーあかりと信頼な中を待つ
Retaining the heat, building up a fumarole, waiting in bright trust
新しい自分をこの目でキャッチョン変わらないものを胸に
Catching a new self with these eyes, holding something unchanging in my heart
歩んでいこう点と線繋ぐものの合間にはエンドレス、こんなね
Let's walk on, connecting dots and lines in between, endless, like this
解き澄ますせんけいの目切り上げるスニーカーらせまでじま
Sharpening the eyes of the line, finishing up sneakers...
先誇れラヘンナ春が来た、サクラミラージュ
Bloom proudly, La Henna, spring has come, Sakura Mirage
咲いて儚いね笑ってエンドレス揺れながらまだ夢の中へそっと囁いて叶えてStep for me
Blooming fleetingly, laughing endlessly, swaying, still into a dream, softly whispering, making it come true, step for me
カメラ、カメラ、離さずいくずきまもないLife is ポッパ、ハラビダ
Camera, camera, going without letting go, life with no time to catch breath...
一期一会、今この瞬間を大切にラブストーリーきらり輝いたStay for me
Once-in-a-lifetime encounter, cherishing this very moment, a love story shining brightly, stay for me
カメラ、カメラ、離さずいくずきまもないLife is ポッパ、ハラビダ
Camera, camera, going without letting go, life with no time to catch breath...
足音が決まり文句じゃお定まりなシナリオとやりがーる
Footsteps are cliché, a stereotyped scenario and play girl
おやおや直撃しながら気取ろうぜトップシステム不滅のニューヨーク
My my, while taking a direct hit, let's act cool, top system, immortal New York
ずっと飾らない君でいて一つだけの温度で誰かが奏でた
Always stay the true you, someone played at a single temperature
燻んでは目覚めてメロディーこの国に呼んで恋して
Smoldering and awakening, melody, calling to this country and falling in love
春が来た、サクラミラージュ。咲いて儚いね笑ってエンドレス
Spring has come, Sakura Mirage. Blooming fleetingly, laughing endlessly
揺れながらまだ夢の中へそっと囁いて叶えてStep for me
Swaying, still into a dream, softly whispering, making it come true, step for me
カメラ、カメラ、離さずいくずきまもないLife is ポッパ、ハラビダ
Camera, camera, going without letting go, life with no time to catch breath...
一期一会、今この
Once-in-a-lifetime encounter, now this...
staring into your eyes make me feel alive
それは始まりの合図
That's the signal of the beginning
Are you ready for this?
柔らかな風 ほら 春めいて
A soft breeze, look, it feels like spring
共鳴するファンファーレ
Resonating fanfare
桜花爛漫 染める桃色
Cherry blossoms in full bloom, dyeing everything pink
別れの予感はソメイヨシノ
The premonition of farewell is Yoshino cherry
I'll be there, I'll be there
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
みんな楽しんでくれたりやー？
Did everyone have fun?
最高潮！最高！
Peak excitement! Awesome!
最高の思い出にしよう！
Let's make it the best memory!
みんな見てくれて本当にね、ありがとうね！
Thank you so much for watching, everyone!
花火だ！綺麗！
It's fireworks! So pretty!
このあと20時45分から、「サクラミラージュ」のパフォーマンスビデオがプレミア公開されますので
Starting at 8:45 PM tonight, the performance video for "Sakura Mirage" will premiere,
たくさん見てください！見てねー、20時45分からだよー！
so please check it out! Watch it, starting at 8:45 PM!
ありがとう！桜ミラージュ、皆さんありがとうございました！
Thank you! Thank you all so much for Sakura Mirage!
またね、バイバイ！
See you later, bye-bye!